<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>VPS on Modeling of Everything</title>
    <link>http://shuod.github.io/tags/vps/</link>
    <description>Recent content in VPS on Modeling of Everything</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://shuod.github.io/tags/vps/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Installing octopus 6.0 (Serial) in Centos 6.8 </title>
      <link>http://shuod.github.io/post/install-octopus-5/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jan 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shuod.github.io/post/install-octopus-5/</guid>
      <description>Octopus is a scientific simulation software for solving quantum problem. (http://www.tddft.org/programs/octopus/wiki/index.php/Main_Page)
Recently, there is a new version 6.0 released (2016-09-05), which has a major improvement. Here we try to install it on the Centos 6.8 (with minimal installation)
First, install Centos 6.8 with minimal installation choice. Installation of octopus 6 mainly follow their manual here : http://www.tddft.org/programs/octopus/wiki/index.php/Manual:Building_from_scratch
1. install several compilers to use. You can check your current available compilers by</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Upgrade python to version 3.5 in Centos 6.8 and deploy flask web app framework  (updated on 20170604)</title>
      <link>http://shuod.github.io/post/upgrade-python3-centos6-deploy-flask/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 13 Sep 2016 10:33:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shuod.github.io/post/upgrade-python3-centos6-deploy-flask/</guid>
      <description>Updated on 20170604: I put in more content to setup on tools chain for python development environment. Extra options were deleted.
I bought a VPS from ramnode last time (last blog), so I guess it is a good time to deploy some web application on it. Since the python came with Centos 6.8 is kind of old (python 2.6), the first step I take is to upgrade the python compiler in Centos 6.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to setup a static blog site using Hugo (hosted on github)</title>
      <link>http://shuod.github.io/post/first/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 10:33:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shuod.github.io/post/first/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Huog is a blog generating system written in go. You could give the article in Markdown format and it will then render the article into html files. Github.com is the place where it uses git to do the version control and they now provide each account a static blog system. So combine the two together, we then have an ideal personal blog with version control. This will include the following topic:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Generate a blog site using hugo&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Host the webpage source code on github.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Host the hugo output(webpage to show) on github.com&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup a Virtual Private Server(VPS) from Ramnode and benchmark it</title>
      <link>http://shuod.github.io/post/setup-a-vps-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Aug 2016 10:33:28 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shuod.github.io/post/setup-a-vps-server/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Virtual Private Server (VPS) is a new way to host a personal server. It hides the hardware detials from the user (which is safe) and delivers a flexible (sometime even real time adjustable) performance to the server. They usually have two types: KVM and OPENVZ. The difference of the two virtualization method is the the OPENVZ is container-like, which is also limited to linux only, but KVM use the main OS system to simulate the hardware for user-OS, which theoretically allows any type of the operation system. Because of the working principle of KVM, it could provide better isolation (Those guys doing virus analysis would like this). However, if you are looking for better performance of the Linux system, openvz maybe a better choice.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;VPS from commercial providers is a perfect source to setup a personal server. This article will include:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Bought a VPS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;

&lt;li&gt;&lt;p&gt;Benchmarking the performance of the VPS&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;​&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>