<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Development on Modeling of Everything</title>
    <link>http://shuod.github.io/tags/development/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Development on Modeling of Everything</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <copyright>Shuo</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://shuod.github.io/tags/development/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Setup WSL2 (windows subsystem linux 2) in windows 10</title>
      <link>http://shuod.github.io/post/setup-wsl2-windows-subsystem-linux-2-in-windows-10/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 20 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shuod.github.io/post/setup-wsl2-windows-subsystem-linux-2-in-windows-10/</guid>
      <description>Ever since Microsoft changed the CEO, it embrace open source world by annoucing new tools (VS code) as well as adding new functions to windows. Now windows 10 become more friendly for developers. The function we are going to test today is one of them.
Background on WSL1/WSL2/Docker Thanks to the architecture of windows NT, it can actually &amp;ldquo;Simulate&amp;rdquo; any operation system (OS) in the system level. (check the figure below) So theoretically, windows is just a &amp;ldquo;Frontend&amp;rdquo;, it can be changed to any other systems.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Kick start docker for a deeplearning environment</title>
      <link>http://shuod.github.io/post/kick_start_docker_for_a_deeplearning_environment/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Dec 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shuod.github.io/post/kick_start_docker_for_a_deeplearning_environment/</guid>
      <description>1. what is docker The first virtualization machine I setup was back to VMWare era. At that time, by using VMWare, you can install linux on a windows machine, and it is very useful too. For me at that time, knowing nothing about linux, I have to google everything, &amp;ldquo;how to start X window&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;how to restart service&amp;rdquo;, &amp;ldquo;how to install software&amp;rdquo;. So running the linux in an application-like manner, I can convienetly switch back to browser to search online.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Basics of the github workflow for  a single user</title>
      <link>http://shuod.github.io/post/basics_of_git_workflow_for_single_user/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shuod.github.io/post/basics_of_git_workflow_for_single_user/</guid>
      <description>In an earlier blog article, I wrote down some git workflow involved to in making this github page site (https://shuod.github.io/post/first/). And here, I will briefly write down a memo of github workflow for a single user. It is similar to git or gitlab workflow but more proper for the single user scenario. I assume you had setup an account on &amp;ldquo;github.com&amp;rdquo; and also a new project on github.
​ The streamline of github workflow is like this:</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Scan a directory in python35</title>
      <link>http://shuod.github.io/post/scandir-in-python35/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Aug 2018 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://shuod.github.io/post/scandir-in-python35/</guid>
      <description>As one of my daily works, checking files from simulation results is of course my practical need. Therefore, I am always interested in using different ways to do it. One of my previous post, &amp;ldquo;checking_files_in_subfolders_using_power_shell&amp;rdquo; was on how to use power shell in windows 10 to do this job. Here I am going to test other ways that I used even before powershell script.
1 find This is a Linux command and it is actually my first way to iterate folders to find files, since the operation system I work with in Supercomputer is Linux.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>